## Web Developer • Berlin, Germany

## **Summary**

Developer with a background in graphic design with strong creative and analytical skills in building customized web pages. Experience identifying problems, finding solutions, and building websites and apps from concept, layout to backend/serverside and databases.

#### **Skills & Tools**

#### **Front End Development**

- HTML, CSS, Javascript,
   Typescript Libraries /
   Frameworks (React, Redux,
   Angular, Material, Bootstrap,
   SASS/SCSS, ¡Query)
- AJAX & JSON
- · Version Control (Git)
- Test & Behavior-Driven
   Development (unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing)
- Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo, PWA)

#### **Back End Development**

- NodeJS & Express
- APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google, Firestore, Heroku, Netifly)
- Relational & non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

#### **Education**

- Full-Stack Web
   Development Certificate,
   CareerFoundry,
   Aug 2022 Feb 2023
- BFA in Graphic Design, Fashion Institute of Technology, NY, Aug 2013 - May 2015

## Languages

- English: Native
- German: Beginner
- · Haitian Creole: Intermediate

### **Web Development Projects**

#### myFlix - Personal project, Careerfoundry

Nov 2022

- Created a non-relational movie database (MongoDB) and built a REST API with Node.JS and Express.
- Tested the API endpoints with Postman, wrote clean and concise documentation, deployed the API with Heroku.
- Designed and developed two single-page, responsive front-end applications using React and Angular.

## Meet App - Personal project, Careerfoundry

Jan 2023

- Developed a progressive web app using React to display events from Google Calendar.
- Applied test-driven development, defining user scenarios for Jest (unit and integration), Cucumber (acceptance), and Puppeteer (end-to-end) tests based on user stories.
- Implemented serverless functions using AWS Lambda and used a Kanban board to follow an agile process.

# **Recent Professional Experiences**

# Kyto - UI / Brand Designer

May 2019 - Jan 2022 • Berlin, Germany

- Created a cohesive brand strategy for Kyto, a software as a service company, and new products.
- Developed a new visual identity designing product and developing marketing materials such as stationary designs, PPT presentations, and social media graphics. Also designed the UI for the company's website and mobile app to ensure a consistent brand experience.
- The new company branding, website and mobile design increased customer engagement with sales and a successful company acquisition by Müller Medien.

#### Smunch - Product / Brand Designer

Feb 2018 - Nov 2018 • Berlin, Germany

- Successfully implemented and led a customer-centric product and brand design strategy for Smunch, a food delivery startup.
- Conducted extensive user research and analysis to identify customer pain
  points and areas for improvement in the existing strategy. Improved the user
  experience, including optimizing the ordering process and enhancing the
  website and app's usability. Updated the visual identity for all
  promotional materials.
- The Updated branding received positive feedback from customers and stakeholders, resulting in increased brand recognition and credibility.